SUMMARY

As a Data Analyst with a unique blend of experiences, I specialize in harnessing data to drive strategic decision-making and operational excellence. With a curious mind and a strong drive for learning, I excel in identifying connections between data sets and transforming challenges into opportunities through meticulous attention to detail. My background in music production, education, tourism management, and entrepreneurship has collectively shaped my analytical mindset, and communication skills, and provided a distinctive perspective for data analysis in today's data-driven world.

CONTACT

4

(908) 636-5891



euikyu.wixsite.com/euikyu



euikyu.kim.data@gmail.com



Linkedin: <u>/euikyu-kim</u>



Tableau Public: /euikyu.kim



GitHub: /kimicue

EDUCATION

Certificate in Data Analytics

CareerFoundry, Remote, Berlin, Germany, 2023

Certificate in Data Design & SQL

Portland Community College, Portland, OR, USA, 2020

Associate in Music Business (AA)

Bergen Community College, Paramus, NJ, USA, 2015

Certificate in Film Scoring

UCLA Extension, Los Angeles, CA, USA, 2010

Master of Digital Interactive Music (MM)

Dongguk University, Seoul, S. Korea, 2007

Bachelor in Tourism Management & English translation/interpretation

Kyunghee University, Seoul, S. Korea, 2003

Certificate in Computer Programming

Choongang Computer Institute, Seoul, S. Korea, 1996

SKILLS

Excel | SQL | Tableau | Python | PowerPoint

LANGUAGE

English | Korean

Euikyu Kim

DATA ANALYST

PROJECTS

Preparing for Influenza Season, Medical Staffing Guide

Applies data sourcing, profiling, pivoting, statistical analyzing hypothesis testing & visualizing to analyze the data & answer any ad-hoc business-related questions.

Tools: Excel, Tableau, & YouTube

Interim Report: .pdf | Final Report: Tabeau | Presentation: YouTube |

Rockbuster, Video Rental

Applies data cleaning, joining, advanced filtering, common table expressions & subqueries to analyze the data & answer any ad-hoc business-related questions.

Tools: PostgreSQL and Tableau

SQL Query: .xlsx ★ | Presentation: .pdf 🗹 | Data Dictionary: .pdf 🗹

Instacart, Online Grocery

Applies data wrangling, data quality & consistency checking, merging data frames, exploratory statistical analysis & data visualization using Matplotlib & Seaborn.

Tools: Pvthon

WORK EXPERIENCE

Career Break (2023-Present)

School Bus Driver (First Student, Portland, OR, 2021-2023)

Maintained records, solved problems, and ensured smooth operations through unwavering reliability, heightened safety awareness, and effective communication, resulting in safe and punctual student transportation.

Transferable Skills: Reliability, safety focus, problem-solving, communication, and customer service.

Computer Lab Assistant (Portland Community College, Portland, OR, 2018-2020)

Provided technical support and assistance to students using computer resources, ensured proper functioning of equipment, and aided in troubleshooting software and hardware issues.

Transferable Skills: Technical Support, Customer Service, Problem-Solving, Communication, Time Management, Attention to Detail.

Tech Support Internship (Free Geek, Portland, OR, 2018-2019)

Assisted with troubleshooting and resolving hardware and software issues, provided technical support to users, and contributed to maintaining and optimizing computer systems.

Transferable Skills: Technical Troubleshooting, Customer Service, Problem-Solving, Attention to Detail, Adaptability, Team Collaboration, Time Management, Learning Agility.

Educator / Instructor, Specialized in Digital Sound & Music (2007-2009 & 2012)

- Korea Broadcasting Arts School, Seoul, South Korea, 2012
- Korea College of Media Arts, Sejong-si, South Korea, 2007-2009
- Seoul Theological College, Seoul, South Korea, 2007-2008

Contributed in curriculum development, mentorship, and effective feedback and assessment resulting in great teamwork, adaptability, and time and stress control.

Transferable Skills: Curriculum development, mentorship, teamwork, problem-solving, adaptability, time & stress management, feedback & assessment.

Business Owner & Operator (Tobaccoflower.co.kr, Portland, OR, 2010-2016)

Enhanced customer shopping experience through meticulous attention to detail in product descriptions, images, and website design, resulting in improved accuracy and responsiveness in customer service.

Transferable Skills: Data management, digital marketing, attention to detail, communication, and customer service.

Other Experiences: Music director, composer, and tour conductor

Diverse experience spans customer enhancement, education, and project management in digital music production. These roles encompass data management, digital marketing, safety-conscious transportation, effective communication, and adaptability.